MARYNA ANHELOVA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Vancouver, Canada +1(236)-979-0325 marina.anhelova@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryna-anhelova/http://shch.in.ua/https://github.com/MarynaAnhelova

Specialized in the front-end development for more than 6 years, I have established a solid background in **HTML, CSS**Javascript (ES6), WordPress. Passionate about interactivity and animations, I love to work on creative projects from the design phase to all kind of media! Today, I am looking for new challenges in Vancouver, Canada!

SKILLS

- HTML: ExpertCSS/SASS: Expert
- JavaScript (jQuery): Advanced
- React.js: Beginner
- PHP(WordPress): Intermediate
- WordPress/Divi: Advanced
- **Shopify/Liquid:** Basic
- Figma/Photoshop: Advanced
- GIT: Advanced
- Testing/Debugging: Advanced
- Responsive Web Design:
 - Advanced
- Cross-browser Development:
 Advanced

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Career break | Full-Time Parenting

September 2021 – present

- Took maternity leave and transitioned to full-time parenting while staying engaged in professional development.
- Developing single-page applications (SPAs) using React.js, strengthening front-end expertise for future career
 opportunities.
- **Completing independent projects**, ensuring continued skill growth in JavaScript, WordPress, and performance optimization.
- Engaging in **online courses** and self-learning to stay updated with the latest front-end technologies.

Front-End Developer at UNILIME

July 2017 – August 2021 (remote)

UNILIME is an Award-Winning group of companies that represents years of versatile expertise in software development and web/graphic/product design.

- **Developed new custom themes** based on provided design mockups using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP(WordPress) and other related technologies, helping clients become market leaders in their niche.
- Made the markup of the websites responsive and looking equally amazing on desktop and mobile platforms.
- Customized WordPress themes for small to mid-sized businesses, improving site performance and usability.
- Enhanced SEO rankings by optimizing images, minifying CSS/JS, and implementing schema markup, improving organic traffic
- Streamlined development processes by writing reusable component-based code, increasing development efficiency.
- **Collaborated with cross-functional teams** (design, UX, strategy, and back-end development) to create high-quality digital experiences.
- Performed cross-browser testing & debugging, ensuring seamless performance across all modern browsers and screen sizes.

Front-end Developer at DIAS TEAM

April 2016 – June 2017 (In-office)

DIAS TEAM - Software Development and Consultancy Company, based in Ukraine.

- Transformed website designs into fully functional, responsive web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and
 related front-end technologies, empowering clients to achieve market leadership through high-performing web
 solutions.
- Developed and customized WordPress themes, enhancing usability and optimizing performance for client websites.
- Ensured clean, semantic, and maintainable code, prioritizing performance, accessibility, and best coding practices.

- **Conducted testing and debugging** to identify and resolve front-end issues, ensuring seamless functionality across devices and browsers.
- **Provided technical support and managed customer tickets**, proactively troubleshooting website issues to improve user experience.
- **Collaborated closely with designers and developers** to align front-end implementation with UX/UI requirements and business goals.

EDUCATION

2014 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (Software Development – Major) - SUMY STATE UNIVERSITY